Speaker 1: Marley Dias, who was named after the reggae singer Bob Marley,
was born in Philadelphia in the United States,
to parents of Caribbean descent, and grew up in New Jersey.
At the age of 11, she complained to her mother that in all the books she was asked to read
at school, the protagonists were always white children, or dogs.
Her mother suggested that instead of just complaining, she should try to do something about it.
Marley decided to launch a campaign called #1000BlackGirlBooks,
in order to call public attention to the lack of diversity in children’s literature
and to promote the idea of featuring black girls as the main characters.
Her goal was to collect 1,000 books and donate them to different communities.
The project became a global sensation, and since the launch of the campaign,
more than 13,000 books with black girls as the main character have been donated to libraries,
schools, and community organizations around the world.
She also has spoken about her project to inspirational women such as Michelle Obama,
and at many other high profile events.
Her aim is to ensure that kids know that changing the world should not be something
that feels imaginary, but something that they actually have the power to do.
Speaker 2: Rishab Jain is from Portland, Oregon, in the USA.
When he was a young teenager, a close family friend died of pancreatic cancer.
This cancer is one of the most difficult to treat,
because the pancreas sometimes gets obscured by other organs in the body,
and this makes it very difficult for doctors to kill all the diseased cells,
while sparing as many healthy ones as possible.
When Rishab heard about the low survival rate for patients with pancreatic cancer,
he decided he wanted to do something about it.
He developed an algorithm that uses artificial intelligence to accurately locate and track the pancreas.
The algorithm won the top prize in a competition called the Discovery Education 3M Young Scientist Challenge,
and, at the age of only 14, he was named America’s top young scientist.
With the money he won from the competition,
Rishab set up a non-profit organization to promote STEM subjects
among disadvantaged children and raise awareness of pancreatic cancer.
He continues to be interested in the importance of STEM education for young people
and the potential of artificial intelligence in medicine,
and is now an expert for science and research on various global committees.
Speaker 3: Bali in Indonesia may be a dream holiday destination,
with its beautiful beaches and clear water.
However, Bali has a less glamorous side: the island has a serious problem with plastic pollution.
When sisters Melati and Isabel Wijsen, then aged just 10 and 12,
were swimming one day at their local beach in Bali,
they found themselves surrounded by plastic bags.
They were so upset by the situation that they decided to try to do something about it.
Their heroes were people who had done things to change the world
– Nelson Mandela, Princess Diana, and Gandhi – so, inspired by them,
they set up a campaign called Bye Bye Plastic Bags,
which has been instrumental in the fight to ban plastic bags on Bali.
Through a range of activities, including petitioning both online and offline,
and distributing environmentally friendly bags with fellow teens,
the sisters’ campaign gained international attention, including the support of the United Nations,
and conservationist Jane Goodall.
As a result of their campaigning, in June 2019,
the governor of Bali banned plastic bottles and packaging on the entire island.
Since then, the sisters have spoken at many international conferences and Melati
has made a film, Bigger Than Us, which follows young activists around the world
who have already made a difference.
Their latest project is Youthtopia,
a learning platform empowering a new generation of young people to become change-makers.